Hey, I'm back just walked in you will not believe what showed up on my front door come over
Natalie?
Hey, how's it going? Hey what's up? Do you have coffee? Can I grown up for just a cup?
Yeah, yeah, I got it
Thank you I ran out
no cigarettes
I'm afraid marijuana will be in my life till the very end. I expect to be buried with a little baggie... just sprinklage..
..you know? Ashes to ashes right? Yeah, and it was so funny...I was
...out of the group of kids I
grew up with.. I was the rebel..the hot head..the crazy one.
The one who would drink, the one who would smoke.
Rebel without a cause
The one who always wanted to do all the crazy stuff....the drop out..hahah
There you go. Thank you
Hi, this is operator 89 319 signing in for my shift
Thank you. Hey could you...could you check and see if there are any hours that I can pick up?
Okay, no, that's okay. I'll check back. Thank you
Hi, do you guys buy guitars? Do you guys buy guitars?
Just not in China... Okay. I'm not sure where it's made. Can I bring it in?
Can I bring it in to see? I'm not sure where it's made. Ok...ok.
Hi, I was wondering do you guys buy DVDs?
Okay, great. Thank you. Thank you. Have a good day. Bye
Hi. Hi. I'm Eric from upstairs, number eighteen. Hi Eric, I'm Casey. Um.. what do you know about a cat?
The... the cat that's around the building? Yeah, that cat.
Well... what do you mean what do I know about it? Stop feeding it.
Okay, is there a problem with the cat? Yeah, there's a big problem... Every morning I wake up...there is shit on my mat.. every fucking morning.
ok
Ok? That's it?
I'm sorry, you know it's not my cat.... I feed it sometimes though. Well stop fucking feeding it if it's not yours.
It stops today.
If you feed it again... I'll fucking kill it
Hey
Heeey
How are you doing? How was that coffee? Uh the coffee was really good, thank you... I owe you a cup of coffee
Thank you
I gotta ask you a question?
Ok
You're in your kitchen. You're on the phone...every time I'm in the courtyard...that's all I see..what's up with that?
Well...um..
Yes, I am.... I work from home actually so I'm an operator for an insurance company
Cool
Um that's not really cool. Yeah, it's pretty it's pretty lonely
and isolating
I don't really talk to like any actual live people. It's just people calling in
All day calling with the same question. You never see a live person? No not really....
Except for you! Yeah, sorry haha
All my life right, okay, born and raised. Love it
That's cool. I'm actually I'm thinking of going back home.
It's not really working out here.
Back to mom and Dad?
No, they're not alive anymore, so I'm gonna go try and save up and move back with my cousin.
I see.
All right, I'm looking forward to moving home.
Alright, well. I'm hitting it, I'm out. Ok.
Have a good night
take care
Bye
or
Hi, I'm it number three at five two two Detroit..
and I need to see if it's possible if I could please pay half of my rent tomorrow
And then I would for sure have the rest by the end of the week?
Oh my God, I was thinking of you. Oh my God. I was thinking of you.
There's this game. It is amazing. It's called hunting. I'm not really into video games.
It's not a video game
if you got a smartphone or
a computer... it's an app and this app puts markers on one of those like GPS maps, right?
ok so these maps..
Have these markers and these markers have these treasures and these treasures are left by people
oh like treasure hunting?
Pretty much adult treasure hunting treasure hunting for us big kids okay, and I thought of you...
What is it called? Hunting?
HUNTING
You have to download the app? Is it expensive?
It's free.
Hello Hunter! It's Gator 23105
If you're in the alley.. you're on the right track! Keep looking by the fence..oh..
..by the way, I lost my pen cap. Hope you can find it...
...and if you can't find it, there's something wrong with you. Happy Hunting!
All better now? I hope so.
It'll be fine..I mean...come on.
I swear I saw someone..it's so weird.
Maybe was just a shadow. Maybe it was just dark I have a lot of shit in there, too
Yeah, that's trippy. You got something going on...there's a lot more here to Casey, isn't there?
I just need to clean...a lot of clutter.
Well it's like my studio, so I have everything in there and then I just start stuff
And then don't finish it and move on to the next thing and before you know it..it looks like that.
All right
What kind of art you doing?
Just painting right now painting whatever sometimes sketching
I mean what you doing dogs, or you know skeletons, and you know.. what?
Well birds..I have the birds right now but..
Just whatever like I want to do a juke box. I think it's more about the colors.
Jukebox. Yeah, I like that
Dig it I dig it
You okay? Yeah, I just feel really stupid. Sorry
Hello, everybody. My name is Casey. This is Casey
Hi, everybody. My name is Casey Ullman. Thank you for checking on my blog. I just started hunting for...
Hi, everybody. My name is Casey Ullman and I'm new to hunting and so I just..
I'm
going to be starting to videotape my
hunts for the blog
so I hope you find them and ....I hope you find them!
and...
You know... find your you know happy hunting let's go hunting
No...your information is what you're going to enter there. Yes, that would be your birthday
Okay, no problem. OK, thank you for calling world energy insurance. Have a great day.
Hello Hunter! This should be a very easy hunt. I have placed it for my art project
please be a part of it and take your photograph with the camera found inside
The hunt lies in a shallow grave at the base of the tree in front of you
If you would like a copy of the finished project, please leave your address
Happy hunting
Hey everybody
Thanks for checking on my blog again. It's Casey and I made it out of the city into the woods today and
Looks like there's a lot of hunts in these woods, so
Let's go find them
This says I'm five feet away from it. I see trash and a shoe and
And I think a bag of shit um but if you want you're more than welcome to come and look with me
Let's go
and
that's
That's the bag
looks like a bag of shit, and I don't want to open it up, so
They just want to eat
Hey guys its casey here. Thanks for coming out with me today
I didn't find anything that it's been really pretty and a lot of fun
so thanks for coming out with me and if you want check it out check out my blog again tonight
because I'm going to go out again and
Go see if I can find something this time, so hopefully ..hopefully you'll come along. Have a good day. See you tonight
Hi this operator 899319 checking to see if there any available shifts to pick up
Hello Hunters, Jessica 83 here and welcome to my first Hunt!
If you're at my hunt, then you're a brave soul. This one comes all the way from Montana
And is especially amazing because I placed it on my trip to LA
We walked through here on our way to a concert at the bowl
and I thought this was the perfect place for a hunt so here we are
You'll have to do some looking
but it's worth the effort. If you can get past the piss smell you'll be fine. The tunnel
look dangerous, but it's not people walk through here all the time
Anyway, I wish you the best of luck and as always
Happy hunting
G'Day hunters Ozzy Jack here
I'm here in Los Angeles from down under visiting my daughter her and her friends don't know about this hunting business
So they think I've lost my mind wandering around the dirty bits of Hollywood looking for these
This one is in the nastiest smelling tunnel. I've ever been in. It's the truth.
Just awful quite interesting though, and it's not too difficult to find. My daughters stayed out there on the road wouldn't come in
Anyway, I've left a treat from Australia in there for you, best of luck and happy hunting
Hi Guys Casey here
so tonight
The hunt I went on it was I should have just trusted my instinct probably if you go on it's pretty cool. It's um
if you're like a thrill seeker
It's good to a good location for that. It's the
The clues that were given to me. We're definitely
Accurate because it smells pissy. It's just piss infected piss soaked it smells
It has an interesting artwork though. I didn't even get to find the
Hunt though because by the time I got in there I got freaked out by a partygoer from the Hollywood Bowl
And then continue to almost get trampled by the rest of them after that so it wasn't even worth it
So definitely I would say go if you want to
if you can stand the piss smell and
Also, check to see what's going on at the bowl check to see what's going on in the area
I'm out hunting again today
um
Last time I came out. I didn't find anything so I just decided that today I'm going to stay out here until I do
It's kind of a cloudy day today, but that's okay. It's not so hot that way
Um
Yeah, so
So far. I've found two today. They were really obvious though, so I just kind of lucked out I think
But not going to complain they're all over in this
Canyon here, so I'm just going to try and find as many as I can and
I hope you come with me. I gotta hurry though, because it's gonna get dark soon, so
I think there's one over here
So I know I'm probably overreacting but I could swear that that man or that woman
or whatever is following me
I'm trying to find the exit to the highway on this side. I think a lot of homeless people come out of here at night
Ok I can hear people walking on the trails. I just can't find them. Ridiculous.
Shit great. I just drop the camera
How did I get in here?
You're gonna love this
in your closet
If you ever used it
There's a hole in there
You'll never guess where that hole goes
my closet! hahahaha
Don't worry. I'm Gonna Share
What?
What ?
Always gotta know something well, what do you want to know?
Why are you doing this to me?
Do you know how stupid you are? You caught me
and then you went over there to me to get the boogie man out
hahaha
I am the boogie man.
Don't worry...you don't hear nothin. They don't care about you..
I wonder how long it's gonna take for your mommy and Daddy
to notice you're gone
Oh wait. They're dead. That's right. They're gonna know right away hahahah
I just can't decide
I mean, you should I tie a bag over your head and just sit and watch it burn out or
Should I use a toy?
you ever fainted?
You're probably gonna
Do that a few times tonight
and you're strong one, but
I'm gonna break you
You're gonna drift in and out
You know what this is?
Haha, it's a fucking saw
Right.. little over here. Oh look at you. God
You are fun
You're good sport. You really are
You know girl?
You can only die once
I'm gonna help you be
Finally successful at something. You're gonna do this really really well. I'm gonna help you through the whole process
You might enjoy it
If you could have seen your face
operator 89319